<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>My dearly beloved Friends and brethren whom the Lord hath reached unto, and visited with his heavenly power, by which you have been gathered to himself to eat of the finest of the wheat.</title>
            <author>Hubbersty, Stephen, 1632?-1711.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1670</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B03700</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC"> 10741497</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing H3214</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 4152.f.20[23]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R28703</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99889570</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99889570</idno>
            <idno type="VID">183706</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B03700)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 183706)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; B1:5[16])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>My dearly beloved Friends and brethren whom the Lord hath reached unto, and visited with his heavenly power, by which you have been gathered to himself to eat of the finest of the wheat.</title>
                  <author>Hubbersty, Stephen, 1632?-1711.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>3, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1670]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Dated and signed at end: Stephen Hubbersty ; Middlesex, the 20 of the 9th month, 1670.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  England --  Pastoral letters and charges --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Judith Siefring</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:183706:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 15 -->
            <head>My dearly beloued Friends and Brethren whom the Lord hath reached unto, and viſited with his heavenly power, by which you have boen gathered to himſelf to eat of the fineſt of the Wheat.</head>
            <p>MY love once more in the Covenant of Eternal life, and love is to you all, being often in my remembrance night and day, with ſufferings with you who ſuffer, and with pray<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers to the Almighty God that you may all ſtand faſt, ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving your loins girt about with truth, and ſhod with the power of the Almighty, that no bryers nor thorns may ſtop nor hinder you in the paſſage to your good Land, but go through them in the hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>venly ſeed, that none of you may want bread, nor water to drink, For God hath ſet open his Heavenly Fountain of living Waters <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>or all his Children to drink at, but old <hi>Belial and his ſons</hi> would ſtop theſe living ſtreams, that the Sons of God might not be re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>freſhed to ſtand againſt all his fiery darts and temptations; for Friends it is the injoyment of the ſweet preſence of God, which will incourage you all to ſtand, not forſaking the aſſembling of your ſelves together, to worſhip the Lord as the Saints uſed to do in the primitive times, for we are come bleſſed be God, to the primitive ſpirit, the ſpirit of Chriſt, which was in the primitive worſhippers, by which they worſhipped God, for which they went through ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny ſufferings as may be read at large in the Scripture, and ſuffered joyfully the ſpoiling of their goods, they knowing a better and a more induring ſubſtance, thus it is that muny of us are come to the ſame ſtage for the ſame teſtimony, and the Devil hath a deſire to try us, and many of his ſlaves is running up and down like <hi>Sauls</hi> to per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſecute the Saints, Well we are Ingaged for the truth, and our peace with God we prize above all, and they have nothing to charge us with juſtly but for worſhipping God, for we wiſh well for the Goverment and all ſouls, that we under them might live a peacea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble life in all honeſty and Godlineſs which ſeems to be ſo ſtruck at, and Vice to grow: Well the God of Heaven hath given us an
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:183706:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 16 -->
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nderſtanding, and a meaſuring line, and an eye to ſee with, by which we ſee, meaſure and underſtand what the effect of theſe things will be, that God will render vengeance in flames of fire, upon un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>godly men, and all who hold truth in unrighteouſneſs, for alas 'tis a vain thing for our enemies to think to affright us by robbing and ſpoyling of us, for our eſtates and lives, though pretious to us, yet nothing in compariſon of the pretious injoyment of the living pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſence of the dreadful God, before whom all men muſt give an ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count, where all Faces ſhall gather paleneſs, whoſe hands hath been imbrewed in the blood of ſufferings of his own ſeed, ſo my fear friends every where my love and life doth flow forth dearly to you, and the Lord arm you all with patience and boldneſs and let all theſe things drive you nearer and nearer to your beloved, and let <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>one murmure and ſay the Lord delayeth his coming, for God will come and plead the cauſe of his own ſeed, and none to ſave ſelf by <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ndirect means, but ſeek to pleaſe your maker, you that honour God God will honour, and keep together in all your meetings, <hi>as ſheep <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>one fold,</hi> for the Devil would ſcatter you whom God hath gathe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ed, and feed of the living bread, and keep clear in your under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
               <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>tandings minds and ſpirits, out of reaſoning with fleſh and blood, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>hat no vail may come over any in which the enemy lodges, and <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>he Lord ſanctifie you all to himſelf, that you may be like the ſheep <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>rom <hi>Mount Gilead</hi> every one bearing twain, that there may be no <hi>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>orah</hi> nor <hi>Demas</hi> amongſt us not none like the rich man, who went way ſorrowful when he was to deny all for Chriſt; but that you <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ay be like <hi>Daniel,</hi> and the three Children, and the holy Apoſtles, when they charged them to ſpeak no more in Chriſts name, would <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ot obey, but chuſed rather to obey God, let this be your choice, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd Ages and generations to come will bleſs God for you, as we <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ave done for them who are gone before us; ſo continue in the faith <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd love, and the Lord exalt righteouſneſs in the Earth, and lay low <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e Kingdom of ſin, for <hi>Babilon</hi> muſt fall, and the Lamb muſt reign <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>nd doth reign in many which is the cauſe the Devil is ſo eager, for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>e Fleſh wars againſt the Spirit, and the Spirit againſt the Fleſh,
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:183706:2"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 16 -->
ſo live in the Spirit, and grow in it, and the wonderful counſello<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> preſerve you ſingle hearted, and keep you over all ſtorms, for <gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> calm will come again, and the joy of the Lord which is as the joy of the Harveſt fill all your Souls with joy and peace in believing, and the Lords bleſſings and peace reſt and remain, with and amongſt you all, for ever and ever, <hi>Amen.</hi>
            </p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <hi>Middleſex the</hi>
                  <date>20. <hi>of the</hi> 9th. <hi>month.</hi> 1670.</date>
               </dateline> 
               <signed>
                  <hi>Your Friend and Brother in the Heavenly Seed,</hi> Stephen Hubberſty.</signed>

            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>Let this be read in your Meetings every where.</p>
            </postscript>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
